Finding Aid for the Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Subject files, circa 1950-1987, VI.; Folders 89-98
  - People, circa 1950-1985, VI.A; Folders 89-95
    - Guston, Philip, 1913-1980, 1960-1987, 6 items (Box 4, Folder 90)
      Exhibition catalogue, Philip Guston "Roma" 1971, October 10-31, 1987, David McKee Gallery, New York, N.Y.
    - Johns, Jasper, 1930-, 1977, 1 item; Mark Stevens's article, Super artist: Jasper Johns, today's master, in Newsweek, October 24, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Marcus, Bunita, 1981-1988, 6 items; Six programs or program announcements for performances of music by Bunita Marcus. (Box 4, Folder 92)
      Arranged in chronological order.
    - O'Hara, Frank, 1926-1966, 1963, 1 item; O'Hara's Belgrade, November 19, 1963, in the limited edition run of Adventures in Poetry. (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Takahashi, Aki, 1944-, 1980-1982, 9 items; 3 reviews of Takahashi performances, 4 concert announcements, and 2 programs for performances by Takahashi (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Wolpe, Stefan, 1981-1985, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 95)
      Clarkson, Austin. Stefan Wolpe: A brief catalogue of published works. Sound Way Press 1981
      1985
      Clarkson, Austin Spatial proportions, pitch complexes and organic modes in the late music of Stefan Wolpe November 1985,
  - Topics, circa 1950-1985, VI.B; Folders 96-98
    - High School of Music & Art (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Maps (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Miscellaneous art-related items (Box 4, Folder 98)
- Correspondence, 1958-1987, VII.; Folders 100-198
  Chiefly correspondence received by Feldman related to business matters.
  Arranged into five subseries.
  - General, 1958-1987, VII.A; Folders 99-152
    Only three letters are from Feldman (to James Coover, Director of the Music Library at the State University of New York at Buffalo, soprano Joan La Barbara and to Maria Runfola of the Music Department at the State University of New York at Buffalo). The subject content includes both business and personal matters, but is chiefly related to Feldman's career.
    Arranged alphabetically by incoming or outgoing correspondent, then chronologically within each folder.
    - Albèra, P. (Philippe) September 10, 1980, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing Contrechamps - musique contemporaine (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Åstrand, Hans 1987, 3 items (3 leaves); Representing Royal Swedish Academy of Music (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Block, René December 19, 1984, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Bloom, Victor, 1956- March 10, 1987, 1 item (1 leaf); In regard to the influence of Feldman's past visit to San Diego. (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Blum, Eberhard, 1940- 1985-1987, 2 items (2 leaves); One postcard regarding concerts of Feldman's music in Dusseldorf and Darmstadt and a flyer for a performance of Feldman's composition, For John Cage in Berlin (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Boone, Charles November 12, 1986, 1 item (1 leaf); Regarding a Feldman visit to San Francisco and performances of Feldman's compositions, Why patterns? and Rothko Chapel (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Cage, John undated, 1 item (34 leaves); Cage's radio play in mesostic form, James Joyce, Marcel Duchamp, Erik Satie: an alphabet with an inscription in caption to Morton Feldman. Includes bibliography. The text was published in X: writings ’79-’82, Wesleyan University Press, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Charlton, David, 1946- March 14, 1967, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing University of Nottingham Music Society regarding a publication of an interview given there in May 1966 by Feldman (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Columbia University 1965, 3 items (3 leaves); Invitations and pamphlet for the Commemoration of Edgard Varèse, Columbia University, December 15, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Coover, James, 1925-2004 May 21, 1980, 1 item (1 leaf); Note from Feldman to Coover regarding William Colleran, legal trustee of Feldman's musical estate. (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - County of Huntingdon and Peterborough (England) 1966, 3 items (5 leaves); Three letters concerning a lecture given by Feldman in Huntingdon, England. Correspondence includes: Robert Rowland-Jones to Morton Feldman, Oriel Glock to Anna Lockwood, and Derek Young to Anna Lockwood. (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965 September 12, 1958, 1 item (2 leaves); Regarding contract between New Music Edition and Theodore Presser (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Cunningham, Merce August 25, 1958, 1 item (1 leaf); Regarding a collaborative performance, probably of Feldman's composition, Ixion (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Dix, Dave May 10, 1982, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the Davenport Community School District (Davenport, Iowa) regarding a lecture given by Feldman to sixth-graders at Lincoln School. (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Duffy, John, 1928- 1981-1986, 2 items (2 leaves); Representing Meet the Composer, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Enke, Heinz December 17, 1984, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing Hessischer Rundfunk (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Freeman, Betty January 20, 1986, 1 item (1 leaf); Thank-you note for presentation on January 12, 1986. (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Frost, Everett May 5, 1987, 1 item (1 leaf); Originally with cassette of a performance of Feldman's composition, Words and music. (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Guston, Philip, 1913-1980 1961-1968, 2 items (2 leaves); One postcard and one letter. (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Harrington, David, 1949- November 16, 1981, 1 item (1 leaf); Writing also on behalf of the Kronos Quartet, about recent performance of Feldman's String quartet in Venice. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Herman, Martin, 1953- September 12, 1978, 1 item (3 leaves) (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Inglis, Frances, 1910- February 14, 1966, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the University of California, Los Angeles. Fine Arts Productions Committee (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Jones, Nancy June 9, 1987, 1 item (2 leaves); Representing the Detroit Institute of Arts. Education Dept. regarding a project to supply a score for a film about the work of artist Patrick Ireland. (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Josee Voormans Production January 24, 1987, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the Holland Festival regarding a work commissioned for performance by the Schoenberg Ensemble on June 12, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Julien, David A. October 21, 1985, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the American Society of University Composers regarding an invitation to participate in the International Year of Canada musical events. (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Kitaj, R. B. November 3, 1966, 1 item (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Kondo, Jo, 1947- May 16, 1985, 1 item (1 leaf); Writing with an invitation to participate at the Interlink Festival. (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - La Barbara, Joan, 1947- April 23, 1982, 1 item (1 leaf); Photocopy of note from Feldman to La Barbara regarding performance of his composition, Wind. (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Marcus, Bunita 1981, Includes photocopied pages from Marcus's notebook on compositional technique, a party invitation, Marcus's program notes for Feldman's composition, Spring of Chosroes, and material related to work performed by Marcus editing and typing Feldman's article, Crippled symmetry.; 8 items (36 leaves) (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Menil, John de July 16, 1971, 1 item (2 leaves); Concerning the possible use of music from Feldman's composition, Rothko Chapel, for a film being made about the chapel (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Mitchell, Breon May 17, 1984, 1 item (12 leaves); Offprint copy of Breon Mitchell's article, A Beckett bibliography: new works 1976-1982, from the Spring 1983 issue (v. 29, no. 1) of Modern fiction studies. (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Morland, Dorothy November 2, 1966, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the Institute of Contemporary Arts (London, England) (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Morot-Sir, Edouard December 12, 1967, 1 item (1 leaf); Writing as Cultural Counselor Representative of French Universities in the United States to invite Feldman to meet Olivier Messiaen and Yvonne Loriod (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - New York Philharmonic 1964-1986, 3 items (3 leaves); January 28, 1964 Rehearsal schedule for performance of Feldman's composition, Out of Last Pieces, signed Joan Bonime October 13, 1983 Invitation to concert and reception in honor of the 100th anniversary of the birth of Edgard Varèse, signed by Alice Tully June 12, 1986 Letter from Composer-in-residence, Jacob Druckman, thanking Feldman for making his composition, Coptic light, available for performance at the Horizons '86 concert series. (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Pavia, Philip, 1915-2005 February 5, 1964, 1 item (1 leaf); Postcard with congratulations on an interview in the New York Times. (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Peragallo, Mario December 3, 1974, 1 item (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Press, Vera M. (Vera Maurina), 1896?-1969 January 27, 1966, 1 item (1 leaf); Christmas card with thanks for his participation in a gift for her pupils. (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Schneider, Urs Peter, 1939- May 24, 1985, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the Konzertgesellschaft neue horizonte Bern (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - Seaman, Fred September 26, 1979, 1 item (1 leaf); Rejecting invitation to John Lennon to participate in June in Buffalo 1980 (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - Silver, George May 8, 1982, 1 item (1 leaf); Invitation to dinner in honor of Feldman (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - Simpson, Robert, 1921-1997 August 1, 1966, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the British Broadcasting Corporation (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Speach, Bernadette, 1948- February 21, 1979, 2 items (2 leaves); Note requesting Feldman's recommendation for job positions, including blank recommendation form. (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Dept. 1986, 2 items (3 leaves); Letter from Feldman to Music Dept. faculty member Maria Runfola in which he reports what was accomplished during his sabbatical. A handwritten note is included informing him of the need to attest that no additional income was received during his sabbatical. (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Takahashi, Aki, 1944- April 23, 1982, 1 item (1 leaf); Note informing Feldman about performances of his composition, Triadic memories. The note from Takahashi is written on the verso of a photocopy of 1 leaf of a letter dated October 5, 1981 to Takahashi, possibly from Bunita Marcus. (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Tanaka, Karen, 1961- March 4, 1987, 1 item (1 leaf); A thank-you note for compositional advice from Feldman. (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - University of Glasgow. Dept. of Music 1976, 1 item (1 leaf); Invitation to concert including music by Feldman. (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Veer, Ad van 't 1984-1987, 2 item (2 leaves); Representing Stichting Nieuwe Muziek Zeeland in asking Feldman's participation in the 1985 and 1987 festivals at Middelburg. (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Wearing, Catherine November 22, 1984, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the British Broadcasting Corporation in request to interview Feldman for a documentary about Edgard Varèse. (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Wilkins, Grover April 3, 1981, 1 item (1 leaf); Representing the University of Pittsburgh. Music Dept. regarding performance of Feldman's composition, Rothko Chapel (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Wolff, Christian, 1934- August 11, 1964, 1 item (1 leaf); Note about article written by Wolff. (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Wright, Mary C. November 13, 1986, 1 item (2 leaves); Letter about events at California Institute of the Arts after Feldman's visit there. (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 1975, 2 items (2 leaves); Letters in which Xenakis accepts Feldman's invitation to participate in the June in Buffalo festival, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Yama, Ann Stimson 1976, 2 items (2 leaves); Two notes accompanied by photocopies of two different versions of the author's composition, Ostinati (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Unidentified sources 1951-1981, 7 items (7 leaves); Includes party invitation, birthday greetings, welcome home greeting, and telegrams (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Awards, undated, VII.B; Folders 153-154
    Notices of awards granted to Feldman
    Arranged alphabetically by issuing agency.
    - American Music Center (Box 16, Item 2)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters May 26, 1970, 2 items; Program from the American Academy of Arts and Letters and the National Institute of Arts and Letters for the ceremony of inducting new members, including Feldman. Accompanied by letter from William Maxwell, president of the Institute. (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain) July 1987, 2 items (5 leaves); Announcement of Radcliffe Award for Graphic Excellence in Music Publishing, Outstanding publication, granted to Universal Edition's 50th anniversary set of 12 scores. Accompanied by note card from William Colleran. (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Business: Contracts, royalties, commissions, and publishing, undated, VII.C; Folders 155-163
    Arranged alphabetically by corporate name and then chronologically within each folder.
    - Broadcast Music, inc. 1981-1983, 16 leaves; Royalties statements (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Composers Recordings, Inc. January 22, 1980, 1 item (2 leaves); Contract for recording of Feldman's composition, Why patterns?, with Composers Recordings, (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Connecticut (State) February 11, 1983, 1 item (1 leaf); Personal service agreement to lecture at the William Benton Museum of Art (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Library of Congress 1961-1975, 4 items (4 leaves); Copyright registration forms for Durations, the payment voucher for commissioning of Instruments II by the Koussevitsky Foundation, and letter requesting brief biography. (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Los Angeles Festival September 1987, 1 item (5 leaves); Letter of agreement between Feldman and the Los Angeles Festival (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - New York Philharmonic 1986, 2 items (3 leaves); Letter from Christopher Berg of the New York Philharmonic attached to commission agreement for Feldman's composition, Coptic light. Two additional photocopies of agreement inserted (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Performing Right Society June 2, 1987, 2 items (6 leaves); Royalties statements (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Universal Edition (London, England) 1985-1988, 6 items; Letters from William Colleran and Robin Anderson of Universal Edition concerning performances of works by Feldman. (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Universal Edition (London, England) 1976-1989, 12 items; Universal Edition catalogs and news publications (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Mark Rothko Foundation, 1971-1972, VII.D; Folders 164-189
    Letters received from twenty-five applicants, or people recommending them, for the Mark Rothko Fund, which granted funds to older artists, writers, and musicians. All but one of the letters were addressed to the treasurer of the Mark Rothko Foundation, Bernard J. Reis. (One letter was addressed to Theodoros Stamos). The letters and supporting materials were forwarded to Feldman for his recommendations. There is one leaf in Feldman's hand with his recommendations regarding the applications.
    The folder containing Feldman's recommendations is placed first in the series, followed by folders alphabetically arranged by name of applicant or recommended person.
    - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Bell, Maria Grant (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Bloeser, Walter (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - Burton, Eldin (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - Diamond, David, 1915-2005 (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Dunne, Herbert Peyton (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Fletcher, Grant, 1913-2002 (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - Frank, Marcel G. (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - Gabriel, Carla (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Garellick, Jack (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Krasner, Louis, 1903-1995 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - La Violette, Wesley, 1894-1978 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Ott, Joseph, 1929-1990 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Parris, Herman M., 1903-1973 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Perle, George, 1915-2009 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Presser, William, 1916-2004 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Reif, Paul, 1910-1978 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Robertson, Patricia (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Rubino, Pasquale (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Spinks, Garland (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Stephan, Arthur W. (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Tuthill, Burnet, 1888-1982 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Weigl, Vally (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Weiner, Lazar, 1897-1982 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Wolfes, Felix, 1892-1971, Letter from Bowman, John S. (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Student papers, 1980-1981, VII.E; Folders 190-197
    Papers written by graduate students in Feldman's Advanced Orchestration Class at the State University of New York at Buffalo, 1980-1981. There are two papers by all but two of the students. None of the papers bear letter grades, but there are a few comments by Feldman written in the margins.
    The folders are alphabetically arranged by student name and then alphabetically by title of the paper.
    - Ames, Charles (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Frounberg, Ivar, 1950- (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Harbold, Mark Allen, 1955- (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Nam, Inhwa, 1956- (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Shepherd, Stuart Paul, 1947- (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Speach, Bernadette, 1948- (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Swartz, Steven Nicolas, 1956- (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Turner, Mark (Box 6, Folder 197)
- Programs and announcements, 1950-1999, VIII.; Folders 198-284
  Announcements and programs arranged in chronological order from 1950-1999. When both announcements and programs are present for a single year, the folder of announcements is filed first. Four folders of undated announcements and programs are filed after the last dated folder; a folder of programs unrelated to performances of Feldman's music is filed last.
  Programs of Feldman's music performed from 1950 through the year of his death, 1987, have been separately indexed. The list below contains links from the programs folders to the index.
  - Programs, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 198)
  - Announcements and programs, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 199-200)
  - Programs, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - Programs, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - Programs, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 203)
  - Announcements and programs, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 204-205)
  - Announcements and programs, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 206-207)
  - Announcements and programs, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 208-209)
  - Programs, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 210)
  - Programs, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 211)
  - Announcements and programs, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 212-213)
  - Announcements and programs, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 214-215)
  - Announcements and programs, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 216-217)
  - Announcements and programs, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 218-219)
  - Announcements and programs, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 220-221)
  - Announcements and programs, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 222-223)
  - Announcements and programs, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 224-226)
  - Announcements and programs, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 227-228)
  - Announcements and programs, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 229-230)
  - Announcements and programs, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 231-232)
  - Programs, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 233)
  - Announcements and programs, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 234-235)
  - Announcements and programs, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 236-237)
  - Announcements and programs, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 238-239)
  - Announcements and programs, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 240-241)
  - Announcements and programs, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 242-243)
  - Announcements and programs, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 244-246)
  - Announcements and programs, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 247-248)
  - Announcements and programs, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 249-250)
  - Announcements and programs, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 251-252)
  - Announcements and programs, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 253-254)
  - Announcements and programs, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 255-256)
  - Announcements and programs, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 257-258)
  - Announcements and programs, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 259-261)
  - Announcements and programs, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 262-263)
  - Announcements and programs, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 264-265)
  - Announcements and programs, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 266-267)
  - Announcements and programs, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 268-269)
  - Announcements and programs, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 270-272)
  - Programs, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 273)
  - Programs, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 274)
  - Programs, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 275)
  - Programs, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 276)
  - Programs, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 276a)
  - Programs, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 277)
  - Programs, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 278)
  - Programs, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 279)
  - Undated announcements (Box 11, Folder 280-281)
  - Undated programs (Box 11, Folder 282-283)
  - Miscellaneous, non-Feldman programs, undated (Box 11, Folder 284)
- Clippings, 1960-1997, IX.; Folders 286-489
  More than two hundred clippings from 1960-1997. Approximately 10 obituaries are included. Sources of clippings include newspapers and periodicals in the United States, Canada, England, Italy, France, The Netherlands, and Germany.
  Arranged chronologically, and then alphabetically by name of the publication. A folder of undated clippings is placed last in the sequence.
  - January 1960 High Fidelity (Box 12, Folder 286)
  - February 20, 1960 The Nation (Box 12, Folder 287)
  - February 3, 1962 The Nation (Box 12, Folder 288)
  - January 1963 High Fidelity (Box 12, Folder 289)
  - August 1963 Harper's (Box 12, Folder 290)
  - January 1964 Show (New York, NY) (Box 12, Folder 291)
  - February 2, 1964 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 292)
  - May 17, 1964 New York Herald Tribune Sunday Magazine (Box 12, Folder 293)
  - December 2, 1964 New York Herald Tribune (Box 12, Folder 294)
  - March 1, 1965 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 295)
  - November 21, 1965 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - December 19, 1965 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 297)
  - December 22?, 1965 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 298)
  - April 15, 1966 New York Post (Box 12, Folder 299)
  - April 15, 1966 New York World Telegram and Sun (Box 12, Folder 300)
  - May 14, 1966 Daily Telegraph (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 301)
  - May 21-22, 1966 New York Herald Tribune (Box 12, Folder 302)
  - May 22, 1966 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 303)
  - October 23, 1966 New York World Journal Tribune, Illustration by Howard Kanovitz (Box 12, Folder 304)
  - February 26, 1967, from unknown source (Box 12, Folder 305)
  - March 5, 1967 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 306)
  - December 1968 Vogue (Box 12, Folder 307)
  - January 5, 1969 London Sunday Times (Box 12, Folder 308)
  - February 23, 1969 Sunday Oregonian (Portland, OR) (Box 12, Folder 309)
  - February 24, 1969 The Oregonian (Portland, OR) (Box 12, Folder 310)
  - May 1969 Cosmopolitan (Box 12, Folder 311)
  - July 10, 1969 Financial Times (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 312)
  - September 15, 1969 Dagens Nyheter (Stockholm, Sweden) (Box 12, Folder 313)
  - March 25, 1970 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 314)
  - March 7, 1971 Houston Post (Box 12, Folder 315)
  - July 28, 1971 Spectacles? (Box 12, Folder 316)
  - November 1, 1971 De Volkskrant (Amsterdam, Netherlands) (Box 12, Folder 317)
  - November 4, 1971 Il gazzettino (Venice, Italy) (Box 12, Folder 318)
  - November 1971 Die Welt (Berlin, Germany), Could be from Hamburg. (Box 12, Folder 319)
  - February 16, 1972 New York Times (Box 12, Folder 320)
  - March 19, 1972 The Observer Review (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 321)
  - October 8, 1972 Courier Express (Buffalo, NY) (Box 12, Folder 322)
  - October 26, 1972 The Listener (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 323)
  - November 21, 1972 Courier Express (Buffalo, NY) (Box 12, Folder 324)
  - November 1972 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 325)
  - January 23, 1973 Daily Telegraph (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 326)
  - January 23, 1973 Financial Times (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 327)